<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Hajj Dost</string>


    <string name="alHaram">Kaaba is called Baitullah or the house of Allah. It is the delight of a Muslim. So In Masjid Al Haram you will see Kaaba, Safa, Hajr-e-Aswad, Maqam e Ibrahim, Safa and Marwah. And drink the Blesses ZamZam water.Al-Masjid Al-Haram is in the city of Mecca, Saudi Arabia. It is the largest an oldest mosque in the world an surrounds ane o Islams holiest places, the Kaaba.It is considered the holiest place on Earth by Muslims. The mosque is also known as the Grand Mosque. This mosque has nine minarets. Like Masjid al-Nabawi in Medina, it also has undergone many renovations and expansions. The latest expansion was during King Fahds reign. Further expansion was planned by the former ruler, King Abdullah.Great Mosque of Mecca, Arabic al-Masjid al-Ḥarām, also called Holy Mosque or Haram Mosque, mosque in Mecca, Saudi Arabia, built to enclose the Kaʿbah, the holiest shrine in Islam.</string>
    <string name="masjidAisha">(The second largest Mosque in Mecca)\nMasjid Aisha has a capacity of Capacity, 47,084 worshipers. It is the Place, where people of Mecca put Ihram and people doing subsequent Umrah renew their Ihram.
        Masjid Aisha, also known as Masjid at-Tan’eem marks the place where Ummul-Mu’mineen Aisha (may Allah be pleased with her) went to enter into Ihram for Umrah when the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) told her to do so during the farewell Hajj.
        The masjid lies 7.5 km south from Makkah on the road to Medina and is the closest of all the boundary points.Masjid e Taneem is a mosque in the Al-Hil area about 5 miles away from the Holy Kaaba, in Taneem, which is near Mecca and acts as Miqat (a station for putting on pilgrims garments) for people living in Mecca.This mosque is also known as Masjid -e- Ayesha since Muhammads wife Ayesha had put her Ihram (restriction on Pilgrimage) from this place once. If someone is living in Mecca and wants to perform Umra (pilgrimage to Mecca) then he should go to this place, enter into the state of Ihram (in part by putting on pilgrims garments) and then return to Mecca so that the condition of traveling for the pilgrims is also fulfilled. Muhammad said “Part of the worship of Hajj and Umra is to travel in the way of Allah and to go out of the city.This is quite a big mosque with facilities for baths, ablution and changing, available for pilgrims and those who come to offer regular prayers.</string>
    <string name="masjidJin">According to tradition, this is a mosque situated on the Al Haram Street, where once the Holy Prophet (SAW) was reciting the Holy Qura’an. A group of Jinn passing by heard the recitation and stopped to hear more.
Masjid Jinn, also known as Masjid Haras, is built on the place where the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) drew a line for Abdullah bin Mas’ood (may Allah be pleased with him) who had accompanied him after he had been commanded to recite the Qur’an to the Jinn.
Abdullah bin Mas’ood (may Allah be pleased with him) narrates, “While in Makkah, the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) once said to the Sahabah (may Allah be pleased with them), ‘Whoever wishes to see what the Jinn are all about should come along’. Besides myself no-one else came. When we reached the place in the Ma’la district of Makkah the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) used his foot to draw a circle on the ground. He then instructed me to sit inside the circle. After proceeding a little further, the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) started reciting the Quran. It then happened that Jinn started to arrive in troops as they gathered there. So many came that I could not even see the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) nor hear him. The Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) then continued talking with a group of them until Fajr.
</string>
    <string name="masjidBilal">This was the place of Residence of Hazrat Bilal (R.A) which was later converted to saudi Government.</string>
    <string name="alKhayfMosque">This Masjid is located at the foot of a mountain in the south of Mina, close to the smallest Jamarat. Masjid al-Khayf is a Masjid where virtues are proven in some Hadith.
This masjid is located at the foot of a mountain in the south of Mina, close to the smallest Jamarat. It was at this spot that the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) and numerous other Prophets before him performed salah.
Masjid al-Khayf is a masjid whose virtues are proven in some Hadith. According to a traceable Hadith of Ibn Abbas (may Allah be pleased with him), the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) said: “Seventy Prophets prayed in Masjid al-Khayf.
Yazeed bin Aswad (may Allah be pleased with him) says that when he performed Hajj with the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him), it was at the Masjid Khayf that he performed the Fajr salah with the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him).
Abdullah bin Abbas (may Allah be pleased with him) narrates that it was in Masjid al-Khayf that the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) addressed them. After praising Allah he said: “Allah will set right the affairs of the person whose prime concern is the Aakhirah (Hereafter), Allah will also grant him self-sufficiency and the world will humble itself before him. As for the person whose prime concern is this world, Allah will scatter his affairs, place poverty in front of him and all he will get of this world will be what has been predestined for him.
</string>
    <string name="Muzdalifa">Muzdalifah stretches from the Valley of Muhassar to the mountains of Ma’zamyn. It is four kilometers long and covers an area of 12.25 square kilometers.
This is a view of Muzdalifah, where Hajj pilgrims arrive after sunset from Arafat on the 9th Dhul Hijjah (second day of Hajj). Muzdalifah stretches from the Valley of Muhassar to the mountains of Ma’zamayn. It is four kilometres long and covers an area of 12.25 square kilometers. Referring to Muzalifah, Allah (Glorified and Exalted is He) mentions in Surah Baqarah in the Quran:“When you leave Arafat, then remember Allah at the Mash’arul Haram.” (‘The Sacred Monument’, referring to Muzdalifah according to Abdullah bin Umar (may Allah be pleased with him). During the farewell Hajj, the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) performed the Maghrib and Isha salats together at Muzdalifah. He stayed at the spot where the present Masjid Mash’arul Haram currently is (towards the Qibla side). From there, the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) said:“Although I am staying here, you may stay anywhere throughout Muzdalifah. During Hajj It is waajib to perform Maghrib and Isha together in Muzdalifah at Isha time. Wuqoof (stay) of Muzdalifah is also waajib and it’s time begins from sub’h saadiq and ends at sunrise. If one spent even a little portion of their time in Muzdalifah, he/she will be absolved of this obligation. However, it is best to remain until just before sunrise.
</string>
    <string name="Jamaraat">It is the place where the Hajjis stone the Shaitan during Hajj.
The Jamarat are three stone pillars which are pelted as a compulsory ritual of Hajj in emulation of the Prophet Ebrahim (upon him be peace). They represent the three locations where Ebrahim (upon him be peace) pelted the Shaitan (Satan) with stones when he tried to dissuade him from sacrificing his son Ismail (upon him be peace). The pillars are called ‘Jamarat-al-Ula’, ‘Jamarat-al-Wusta’ and ‘Jamarat-al-Aqaba’.
One of the purposes of the Hajj is to recall, while in Mina, how a 94 year old father brought his eight year old son here for sacrifice. Ebrahim (upon him be peace) had first left his wife and newborn son, Ismail (upon him be peace) in the desert upon Allah’s command. Then while returning after eight years to them he saw a dream wherein a man told him that Allah (Glorified and Exalted is He) wanted him to sacrifice his son. He saw the same dream for three consecutive nights and as he was a Prophet, his dreams were a form of Wahy (Divine Instruction). He realised that Allah (Glorified and Exalted is He) wanted him to sacrifice his son for whom his heart was overfilled with love and emotions. He went to his wife and asked her to dress up Ismail (upon him be peace). Ismail (upon him be peace) was overjoyed that his father had come after such a long time and was now taking him out for a walk. When Hajra (upon her be peace) asked, “Where are you taking him?” He replied, “To meet a friend.”
They then reached Mina. Here Ebrahim (upon him be peace) asked his son that your father has seen such a dream, what is your opinion about it? The reason for asking was not to ask his opinion in deciding whether to go ahead with the command or not. It was to assess whether his son will allow him to follow the command freely or will he have to forcibly carry out this order. In other words, he asked this to test the intensity of love for Allah in his son’s heart. The son replied, “My father, obey the command given by Allah. You will, Insha’Allah, find me steadfast. Give my shirt to my mother as it will be a source of comfort for her and wrap me in your own shirt. Put me face down so you can’t see my face, lest you hesitate in carrying out my slaughter.
</string>
    <string name="mountAbuQubais">Near this is the place where the Prophet (SAW) performed the miracle of splitting the moon in two parts.This large structure, adjacent to Mount Safa, is built on top of Mount Abu Qubais. It is believed that it was from the top of this mountain that the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) pointed to the moon and split it into half.The Hajar al-Aswad (The Black Stone) was protected in it when Allah (Glorified and Exalted is He) sent the flood in the time of Prophet Nuh (peace be upon him).The Umayyad governor Hajjaj bin Yusuf fired a catapult from the top of Mount Abu Qubais onto the Ka’bah during the seige of Makkah in 691 CE. This resulted in the killing of Abdullah bin Zubair (may Allah be pleased with him).
The first ever Mountain created by Allah Almighty. This mountain is directly opposite the Ka’aba close to Mount Safa. Hazrat Adam [AS] took rocks from this mountain when he built the Ka\'aba very first time on earth. After building the Ka\'aba, Prophet Ibrahim [AS] stood on this mountain and called mankind to come and worship Allah. When Hazrat Nooh [AS] flood came the Hajrey Aswad [The Black Stone] was placed over this mountain. When the Holy Prophet [PBUH] first started preaching Islam publicly, he stood on Jabal Abu Qubais and called mankind to submit to Allah. It was whilst he was on this mountain that Holy Prophet [PBUH] split the moon in two. Prophet Mohammad Mustafa [saww] showed the miracle of Splitting the moon into two halves over this mountain.
</string>
    <string name="birthPlace">Situated near “Suq Lail” – Presently a library by the name of “Maktaba Mecca al-Muharramah”.
The Prophet’s (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) father Abdullah died about six months before his birth. He had gone on a trading expedition to Gaza and Syria in the north and on the way back he had lodged with his grandmother’s family in Yathrib (later to be known as Madinah). He became ill, died and was buried there. Thus, the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) was born an orphan.
While his mother Aminah was pregnant, she had a dream that a light was emitted from her lower body that illuminated the palaces of Syria. When she went into labour, Shifa bint Amr, the mother of Abdul Rahman bin Auf (may Allah be pleased with her) served as midwife. Abdul Muttalib received the news of his grandson’s birth with joy. He took the newborn to the Ka’bah and invoked Allah’s blessings and thanks. Believing his grandson would grow up to be highly praised, Abdul Muttalib named him Muhammad, which means ‘he who is praised’. In keeping with Arab tradition, he then shaved the baby’s head and afterwards invited his fellow Makkans to a feast.
In the name of Allah, and peace and blessing upon the Messenger of Allah. The blessed birth place [of the Prophet Muhammad] has the been the center of attention for the whole Islamic nation over the span of 1400 years, remaining a br
        illiant reflection throughout Islamic history, to be seen with utmost clarity by both  the current and coming generations, revisiting immortal memories, and remembering within its vicinity the life of the one “possessed of tremendous character.” This location gets its historical, educational and civilizational importance from the events which took place in it throughout the passage of time. The one about Allah said: “and we have not sent you save as a mercy for all the worlds” was born in it. Multiple narrations by trustworthy historians confirm the specified location is the birth place of the Prophet (peace be upon him).
</string>
    <string name="caveHira">The cave where the Holy Prophet (SAW) used to meditate frequently during the first forty years of his life. This is also the place he received the first revelation.
The cave is situated at a height of 270 m (890 ft). During the season of Ḥajj , an estimated five thousand visitors climb to the cave daily to see the place where Muhammad is believed to have received the first revelation of the Quran on the Night of Power by the angel Jibreel. Often overlooked because of its proximity to the great shrines of Mecca, the Cave of Hira is nevertheless one of the great if underappreciated holy sites of Saudi Arabia.  It was in this tiny cave, barely more than a niche on the side of Jabal An-Nur, that the Prophet spent much of his time during his early adult years; and it was here that he received his earliest divine revelations that would ultimately lead to the founding of the Islamic faith.  Although a stop at the Cave of Hira is not a mandatory part of the traditional pilgrimage to Mecca, a climb up Jabal An-Nur and a peek into the Prophet’s mountainside retreat is nevertheless a very popular detour for visitors to the Holy City.  The cave is often visited in preparation for the final, climactic trek to the Masjid Al-Haram.
</string>
    <string name="caveThawr">The cave where the Holy Prophet (SAW) hid from his enemies when migrating to Medina.
The mountain is notable for housing a cave known as Ghar Sawr (Cave of Sawr), in which the Islamic Prophet Muhammad took refuge from the Quraysh, during the migration to Medina. For most Muslims, the cave is of religious significance, and is thus visited by many pilgrims and the tourists.Cave of Thawr is located on top of mount Thawr with a view over surrounding mountains. It is in the form of a rock or a hallowed rock and looks like an upside-down boat. Its altitude from the ground is a little more than 500 meters. Climbing up to the cave is very difficult and requires making a lot of efforts.Cave of Thawr has two entrances, one in the west which is very narrow and almost at the bottom of the cave, entering from which is very difficult, and another is on the east which is somehow wider and it is believed that it has been made by a miracle from God after the Prophet (s) entered the cave.Length of the cave is about 18 hand spans [about 4 meters] and its width in the middle is 11 hand spans [near to 2.5 meters]. The height inside the cave is about the height of a man and its area is 2.5 cubic meters.
</string>
    <string name="jabalNoor">"Jabal” in Arabic Means Mountain and "Nour" means light or enlightenment.
The mountain houses the famed Cave of Hira . The mountain and its cave hold tremendous significance for Muslims throughout the world, as the Islamic Muhammad (PBUH) is said to have spent a great deal of time in the cave meditating, and it is widely believed that it was here that he received his first revelation, which consisted of the first five ayats of Surah Al-Alaq from the archangel Jibrā’īl جِـبْـرَائِـيْـل, as is pronounced in certain Quran recitation schools and some Arab tribes.It is one of the most popular tourist attractions in Makkah. The mountain itself is barely 640 metres (2,100 ft) tall; nonetheless two hours are needed to make the strenuous hike to the cave.
</string>
    <string name="jannatMualla">(Cemetry in Mecca)\nIt is also known as Al-Hajun. The Prophet (SAW) used to visit it frequently. It is the 2nd holiest graveyard after Baqi.Jannat al-Mualla is a cemetery to the north of the Masjid al-Haram, and near the Mosque of the Jinn, in Mecca, Saudi Arabia. It is the place where Muhammads wife, grandfather, and other ancestors are buried.The Jannatul Mualla Cemetery in Mecca is one of the two most famous graveyards in Islam.  Not quite as famous or historic as its counterpart, the Maqbarat Al Baqi cemetery in Medina, it is nevertheless older and boasts its share of famous gravesites.  The ancestral cemetery of the Banu Hashim and other local Quraish clans, many of the Prophet Muhammad’s ancestors are interred here.  These include Muhammad’s mother and grandfather, as well as his first wife, Khadijah.  Unfortunately, many of the gravemarkers were  removed or destroyed during the 1925 purge.  While little remains to commemorate those who are buried here, many thousands of pilgrims to Mecca still make it a point to visit the ancient hallowed ground of the Prophet’s ancestors.</string>
    <string name="jabalRehma">Jamal Al-Rahmah is a small hillock and it is from this platform that Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) delivered his unforgettable farewell sermon, enunciating for-reaching religious, and economin, social and political reforms.</string>


    <string name="masjidNabvii">When the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) migrated to Medina (then called Yathrib), the chiefs of the city and his immediate followers rode around his camel in their best clothes and in glittering armour.
Masjid-e-Nabwi is the masjid (mosque) established by the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) upon his migration to Madinah. It is the second most revered masjid in Islam and the second largest in the world, after Masjid al-Haram in Makkah.
When the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) migrated to Madinah (then called Yathrib), the chiefs of the city and his immediate followers rode around his camel in their best clothes and in glittering armour. Everyone was hoping he would stop by their house. The Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) would answer everyone politely and kindly, “[This camel] is commanded by Allah; wherever it stops, that will be my home.” The camel moved on with slackened reins, reaching the site of the present masjid and knelt down. The Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) alighted and said, “This is the home” and inquired as to who owned the land. The land contained a few date trees, graves of polytheists, a resting spot for herds of cattle and was owned by two orphan brothers, Sahl and Suhail. The Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) purchased the land, had the trees cleared and the polytheists graves dug up and leveled.
</string>
    <string name="masjidQuba">The virtue of Masjid Quba is mentioned in the following Quranic verse in Surah Tauba. The Peophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) said:”He who purifies himself at his home and comes to Masjid Quba and offers two rakats therein, will be rewarded the reward of Umrah(lesser pilgrimage).
Quba is the place on the outskirts of Madinah where the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him), accompanied by Abu Bakr (may Allah be pleased with him) arrived and first stayed after emigrating from Makkah. They arrived on Monday 12th Rab’i al-Awwal, fourteen years after Prophethood and this date marks the beginning of the Islamic calendar (Hijra), (16th July 622 CE). A masjid was established here by the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him), the first to be built in Islam.
The Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) said: “He who purifies himself at his home and comes to Masjid Quba and offers two rakats therein, will be rewarded the reward of an Umrah.
On arriving in the village of Quba after the blessed Hijra (migration), the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) stayed for several days in the house of Kulthoom bin Hadm (may Allah be pleased with him) and laid the foundations of Masjid Quba on his land. Prior to the migration of the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) the Muslims sometimes offered their Friday prayers at the house of Sa’ad ibn Khaithamah (may Allah be pleased with him) which was close by. The location of this house was included in the modern day extension of Masjid Quba but the location of the house of Kulthoom bin Hadm (may Allah be pleased with him) is marked by a few boulders to the south-west of Masjid Quba.
</string>
    <string name="masjidQiblatain">This is Masjid Qiblatain (Mosque of the two Qiblas). It is historically important to Muslims as this is where in Rajjab 2 AH the revelation of the Quran came to change the direction of the Qibla from Bait-al-Maqdis in Jerusalam to the kaabah in Mecca.
During his time in Makkah, the Prophet Muhammed (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) used to pray towards Bait-al-Maqdis, with the Ka’bah in front of him. When he migrated to Madinah, he prayed towards Jerusalem for 16 months, but he hoped it would be changed to the Ka’bah.
During Dhuhr prayer (or it was said that it was Asar), the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) had led his Companions when he was commanded to face towards the Ka’bah by the following revelation in the Quran in Surah al-Baqarah: “Verily, We have seen the turning of your (Muhammed’s) face towards the heaven. Surely, We shall turn you to a Qiblah (prayer direction) that shall please you, so turn your face in the direction of Al-Masjid Al-Haram (at Makkah).
</string>
    <string name="masjidJuma">This is the first mosque where our Holy Prophet Hazrat Muhammad (P.B.U.H) offered the first khutba of Juma Mubarak on Friday (Yum Al Juma).
Masjid Jummah, on the boundary of Madinah marks the site where the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) led the first Jummah salah, shortly after his Hijrah (migration) from Makkah. It is about 2.5 km from Masjid-e-Nabwi.
Masjid Jummah, on the boundary of Madinah marks the site where the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) led the first Jummah salah, shortly after his Hijrah (migration) from Makkah. It is about 2.5 km from Masjid-e-Nabwi.
Approximately one hundred Muslims participated in this first Jummah salah. Amongst them were the Prophet’s (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) relatives from Bani an-Najjar who had come to meet him and some from Bani Amr who had escorted him from Quba.
After performing the Friday prayer, the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) mounted Qaswa (his camel) and set off for the city of Madinah.
</string>

    <string name="masjidBilalMedina">Masjid Bilal is named after a companion of Muhammad (SAW). Bilal was a former Abyssinian slave who accepted Islam.</string>
    <string name="masjidAbuBakar">This was home of Hazrat Abu Bakar Siddique which was later converted to a Masjid by Saudi Authorities.</string>

    <string name="rozaRasol">The Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) said:”Whoever visits me after my death is like he who had visited me during my life.”
This gold grill is the front part of the Rawdah Mubarak, the Sacred Chamber in which the Prophet Muhammad (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) passed away and where he is buried. It also houses the graves of the first two Caliphs of Islam, Abu Bakr (may Allah be pleased with him) and Umar (may Allah be pleased with him).
With regards visiting Madinah and performing the Ziyarah (visiting the grave of the Holy Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him)), the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) said: “Whoever visits me after my death is like he who had visited me during my life.” [Tabraani] “Whoever performs his Hajj in Makkah, then comes to Madinah with the sole aim of visiting me in my Masjid, for him shall be written (the rewards of) two accepted Hajj.” [Daylami] “When a person stands at my grave reciting blessings on me, I hear it; and whoever calls for blessings on me in any other place, his every need in this world and in the hereafter is fulfilled and on the day of Qiyamah I shall be his witness and intercessor.
The Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) was buried in the house of Aisha (may Allah be pleased with her) in whose house he was staying at the time of his death. The wives of the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) lived in small, simple huts adjacent to the masjid. Each hut consisted of a room which was approximately 5m x 4m with a small backyard and were made of unbaked bricks of mud with branches of palm tree as a roof covering.
</string>

    <string name="riyaadUlJannah">The area between the sacred chamber and the pulpit (Mimbar) is known as the Riadhul Jannah i.e. Garden of paradise. It is presently distinguished by a green carpet and is also referred to as Rawdah.
The area between the Sacred Chamber and the Pulpit (Mimbar) is known as the Riadhul Jannah i.e. Garden of Paradise. It is presently distinguished by a green carpet and is also referred to as Rawdah.
Abu Hurairah (may Allah be pleased with him) narrated that the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) said:
“Between my house and my pulpit lays a garden from the gardens of Paradise, and my pulpit is upon my fountain (Al-Kauthar).
Scholars have interpreted the above narration as follows: The Garden is parallel to a garden above it in Paradise. Or it is in reality a garden of paradise, which will be returned to paradise in the hereafter. Or it is like the gardens of paradise, because the peace and tranquility which is experienced in it when engaged in the remembrance of Allah resembles that of paradise.
The original size Is approximately 22 meters in length and 15 meters in width, part of it is in the chamber of the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him).
</string>
    <string name="birUthman">There was a time in Medina when it faced huge shortage of water, due to lack of rainfall. All the wells were dried and barren. Only one well owned by a Jew had water in it.
Bir Uthman  also known as Bir Rumah was a well that was purchased by Uthman ibn Affan (R.A) for the benefit of the Muslim community of Madinah, after the Prophet’s (SAW) arrival in the city.
There was a period in Madina when it confronted enormous deficiency of water, because of absence of precipitation. Every one of the wells were dried and fruitless. Just a single well all around Madina claimed by a Jew had water in it. The Jew proprietor was exceptionally one-sided and sold water on high costs to the Muslims, and offered totally free water to the Jews.

When this news reached the Prophet ﷺ he asked all the Muslims, that whoever buys this well will be granted a house in Jannah.

This narration of the Prophet ﷺ reached Uthman bin Affan, and he instantly decided to purchase that well owned by the Jew. The Jew was only willing to sell half the well. Uthman decided to buy the other half as a Waqf for the Muslims so that they could have free water as much as needed.
</string>
    <string name="birAli">Bir-e-Ali or the well of Ali. When returning from an expedition, the army of Imam Ali once ran out of water. He dug this well from which water continues to flow even today.</string>
    <string name="khandak">The battle of khandaq took place during the time of Prophet. IT is also called as battle of confederates and Surah Al Ahzab was revealed to denote the confederacy of non-believers and Jews against Islam.
The battle of the Trench (Al-Khandaq), or, of the Clans (Al-Ahzaab) (Ibn Hisham, Vol. II, p. 214), as it is sometimes called, took place in the month of Shawwal, 5 A.H. Such armed discord was frought with great difficulties and overcome with comparable courage. It forged and tested the fortitude and patience of the Muslims that would later prove to be of immense benefit to them not only in winning over the Arabian Peninsula as regards their faith but also in taking its message to the distant lands. It was a decisive conflict between Islam and disbelief; of light versus darkness, whereby Muslims were put to the most crucial tests and times never ever experienced before, exactly as the Quran states:
When they came upon you from above you and from below you and when eyes grew wild and hearts reached to the throats and ye were imagining vain thoughts concerning Allah.
The Prophet (peace be upon him) agreed to his suggestion and decided to have a trench dug in the open ground lying to the north of Madinah. The city was exposed to assault only on that side and was well protected to the west, south and east by clumped plantations, volcanic rocky plains and granitic hills, presenting a considerable obstacle to the cause of a mounted army.
</string>
    <string name="jannatUlBaqi">It is praiseworthy to ask Allah Ta’ala for a death in the city of his final messenger (Allah bless him and grant him peace), the illuminated Medina. There is also a great significance in being buried in the al-Baqi graveyard.
Jannatul Baqi (Garden of Heaven) is the main cemetery of Madinah. Buried there are many members of the Prophet’s (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) close family, around ten thousand of his companions (Sahabah) and many prominent, pious personalities.
Aisha (may Allah be pleased with her) reported (that whenever it was her turn for the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) to spend the night with her) he would go out towards the end of the night to al-Baqi and say: “Peace be upon you, abode of a people who are believers. What you were promised would come to you tomorrow, you receiving it after some delay; and God willing we shall join you. O Allah, grant forgiveness to the inhabitants of Baqi al-Gharqad.
The first person to be buried in al-Baqi was As’ad Bin Zararah (may Allah be pleased with him), an Ansari companion who died soon after the Prophet ‘s (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) migration to Madinah. The Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) chose the spot to be a cemetery. The first of the Muhajirun (Emigrants) to be buried there was Uthman bin Mazoun (may Allah be pleased with him) who died shortly after the Prophet (peace and blessings of Allah be on him) returned from the battle of Badr.
</string>
    <string name="mountainHeavenHell">The second largest mountain after Uhud located at the southern boundary of Medina is described as a mountain of hell.</string>
    <string name="wadiJinn">Last but not the least the thrill of visiting Medina is incomplete without visiting the Wadi-e-Jinn.
Wadi al- Jin is also known as Wadi Al-Baida, a mysterious valley or Wadi that is situated in Madinah, some called it Ghost Road as cars move here own their own without drivers touching. It is located 30 km northwest of Madinah and considers Natural Park among dwellers of Madina they came here and erect tents especially at the weekends. First of all let’s describe the meaning of Wadi Al-Jin, wadi means valley while the closest word found near Jin is Genie. Genie or Jins are supernatural paranormal entity or a creature that is made up of fire.
Hazrat Dawood R.A reported from Amir who said: I asked Alqamah if Ibn Masood were present with Allah’s Messenger PBUH on the night of the Jinn. He said: No, but we were in the company of the Prophet SAW one night and we lost him. We rifled for him in the valleys and the hills and said: He has either been taken away by Jinn or has been clandestinely murdered. He the narrator said: We spent the wickedest night that people could ever spend.  When it was dawning we saw him coming from the side of Cave Hira.  He the narrator reported: We said:
        Allah’s Messenger PBUH we missed you and searched for you but we could not find you and we spent the wickedest night that people could ever spend. He SAW said: There came to me requester on behalf of the Jinn and I went with him and recited the Quran to them.  He the narrator said: He then went with him and indicated us their trails and the smidgens of their cinders.  They, the Jinn asked Him PBUH about their endowment and he said: Every bone on which the name of Allah is recited is your provision. The time it falls in your hand it shall be covered with epithelium, and the excrement of the camels, is food for your animals.
</string>

    <string name="hajj_guid_description">Hajj guid step by step</string>

    <string name="open_location_settings">Enable GPS</string>
    <string name="open_internet_settings">Goto Settings</string>
    <string name="open_airplane_settings">Disable Air plane mode</string>
    <string name="title_activity_home_locat">HomeLocation</string>
    <string name="title_activity_current_location">Current Location</string>
    <string name="title_activity_hhplocation">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pray2">Pray2Activity</string>

    <string name="How_to_Perform_Hajj_step_by_step">The Hajj (pilgrimage to Mecca) is one of the five pillars of Islam, the obligations that all Muslims must uphold. Every adult Muslim (male or female) who has the physical and financial means is required to travel to Mecca to perform the Hajj once in his or her lifetime. In Mecca, Muslims from all over the world gather in a display of faith, unity, and solidarity by recreating the ritual that the Prophet Muhammad (peace and blessings of Allah be upon him) performed in his last pilgrimage.</string>
    <string name="Preparing_for_the_Hajj"></string>
    <string name="be_sure_you_are_ready_to_perform_hajj">The Hajj is not to be undertaken lightly or as an afterthought. In ancient times, it was not uncommon for pilgrims to die during their journey to Mecca. Though modern conveniences now allow millions of Muslims to quickly and safely travel to and from the holy city, the Hajj should still be approached with the seriousness and dedication of these early pilgrims. Study the rituals of the Hajj, begin to clear your mind of worldly distractions, and, most importantly, be repentant for past sins, which will be forgiven during your pilgrimage. As with all forms of Muslim worship, the Hajj must be undertaken with sincerity and out of a devotion to God (Allah). The Hajj cannot be performed for the purpose of gaining worldly recognition or material gains in this life. The Hajj must be performed in accordance with the Prophet Muhammad words and deeds (peace and blessings of Allah be upon him) as described in the Sunnah.</string>
    <string name="Decide_which_type_of_Hajj_you_will_undertake"> Muslims have three different options when it comes to performing the Hajj. Each offers a slightly different experience in terms of the rituals performed and the timeline of events on the pilgrimage. The three types of pilgrimage are: 
Tamattu: This is the most common form of pilgrimage and the one recommended by the Prophet Muhammad himself (peace and blessings of Allah be upon him). Tamattu involves the pilgrim performing the rites of the minor pilgrimage ritual known as Umrah, then performing the rites of the Hajj. Pilgrims performing Tamattu are called Mutamatti. As this is the most common type of pilgrimage especially for foreigners to Saudi Arabia the rest of this guide assumes you will be performing this type of pilgrimage.
Qiran: In this option, the pilgrim performs the rites of both the Umrah and Hajj in one continuous act with no "break" in the middle. Pilgrims performing Qiran are called Qaarin.Ifraad: Finally, this form of pilgrimage involves performing only the rites of the Hajj - not of the Umrah as well. This form of pilgrimage is also notable for being the only one that does not require animal sacrifice. Pilgrims performing Ifraad are called Mufrid.
</string>
    <string name="Plan_your_trip_to_Saudi_Arabia">The Hajj takes place in and around the holy city of Mecca, which today is located in the country of Saudi Arabia. As when traveling to any foreign country, you will want to have your passports, travel documents, tickets, and so forth sorted out well in advance. Keep in mind that national governments can sometimes be slow to issue new passports when old ones expire. The Hajj occurs from the 8th to the 12th of Dhul-Hijjah, the 12th month of the Islamic calendar. Because the Islamic calendar is a lunar calendar, the date of the Hajj changes from year to year on the Western Gregorian calendar. Note that, according to the Saudi government, the last day that pilgrims are allowed to arrive at King Abdulaziz International Airport in Jeddah for the Hajj is the 4th of Dhul-Hijjah. The Saudi government offers special "Hajj visas" to American Muslims who have not made the pilgrimage in the last five years.[5] Obtaining one of these visas requires an up-to-date passport, a completed application form, copies of marriage or birth certificates, and an up-to-date immunization record. Pilgrims often travel to perform the Hajj in groups as a sign of solidarity. Contact members of your local Muslim community to see if any are performing Hajj this year - if so, you may want to consider coordinating your trips.
    </string>
    <string name="Prepare_to_be_immersed_in_religion"> As a traditionalist Islamic monarchy, the nation of Saudi Arabia has rules for personal conduct, especially that of women, that may be unfamiliar to foreigners. All women performing the Hajj should plan to travel in the company of a mahram - any related man, such as her father, brother, husband, son, or an approved individual according to Islamic law. Women over 45 can perform the Hajj without a Mahram if they are part of a large group and have a notarized letter of consent from their husband. All people - women and men - who are attending the Hajj should prepare to be exceedingly modest for the duration of their stay in Saudi Arabia. Clothing must be modest and unadorned - for much of the pilgrimage, special religious garb is required for men. Cologne, perfume, makeup, and scented soap should be avoided. When a pilgrim enters the sacred Ihram state of ritual purity, smoking, swearing, shaving, cutting ones nails, and sexual intercourse are forbidden.</string>
    <string name="Peforming_the_Rites_of_Umrah"></string>
    <string name="Assume_Ihram"> Ihram is a holy state of purity that all Muslims must assume before performing the rites of Umrah and Hajj and which must be maintained for the duration of the rituals. Ihram requires certain physical actions and behavioral changes, but dont be mistaken - the real state of purity is attained spiritually by proclaiming ones intention to sincerely pursue the Umrah/Hajj and by reciting the Talbiyah prayer. Thus, someone who assumes Ihram externally but does not have sincere belief in his or her heart is not truly fulfilling Ihram. Men and women enter into Ihram differently - see below for details:
Men: Shave, comb your hair, trim or shape your facial hair, cut your nails, and remove unwanted body hair. Bathe (or perform wudu, partial ablution) with the intention of Ihram, but dont apply cologne or other scents. Sincerely repent for your sins. Clothe yourself in clean, plain Ihram sheets - wrap one around your waist and wear the other over your upper body. Wear simple sandals or flip flops that dont cover the top portion of your foot. Avoid covering your head. These simple garments signify the equality of all before God - the wealthiest king and the lowliest beggar wear the same clothes on the Hajj. Women: As with men, you should shave and groom yourself, bathe, avoid applying scents, etc. You should also avoid applying makeup or other cosmetics. However, besides the requisite sandals, women don\'t have special clothes for Ihram - their ordinary clothes should be used, provided that they are clean and modest.Note that in Islam, covering the head with a veil, scarf, etc. is "mandatory" attire for women and should be done on the Hajj too.
</string>
    <string name="Declare_your_intention_and_say_the_Talbiyah"> A special boundary called a Miqat surrounds the holy sites of the Hajj. Pilgrims cannot cross this boundary without having attained the pure state of Ihram. When a pilgrim in the state of Ihram approaches the Miqat at one of six historical entry points, he pronounces the Niyyah - a short recitation of his intention to complete the Umrah. Then, at the Miqat, the pilgrim recites the Talbiyah, a prayer that will be repeated often during the pilgrimage. The words of the Talbiyah are: Labbayk Allaah humma labbayk, labbayka laa shareeka laka labbayk. Innal hamda wan-ni’mata laka wal-mulk, laa shareeka lak."Here I am O Allah, (in response to Your call), here I am. Here I am, You have no partner, here I am. Verily all praise, grace and sovereignty belong to You. You have no partner."If she or he has not already entered into the state of Ihram, the pilgrim must do so at the Miqat before crossing. Note - it is tradition to enter these holy entryways and most other holy buildings with the right foot first.</string>
    <string name="Proceed_towards_the_Kabah_The_most_sacred_location_in_Islam"> At first sight of the Kabah, keep your eyes fixed on it and stand to the side of the crowd as you say "Allahu Akbar" ("God is Great") three times, followed by saying "La Ilaha Illallah" ("There is no god but God"). Recite other holy verses if you desire. Say a blessing for the Prophet Muhammad (peace be upon him) and, in total humility, make your prayers to Allah. This is an especially propitious, auspicious time to pray for something.</string>
    <string name="Perform_the_Tawaf"> Tawaf is a ritual where Muslims circle the Kabah. To begin, men should make sure their Ihram garb is properly arranged - make sure the upper sheet passes under the right arm and lays across the left shoulder, exposing the right shoulder. Next, all should face the Kabah so that the Black Stone is on your right. Make another Niyyah for Umrah, saying: Allah huma inee ureedul umrata fa yasir haa lee wata qabal haa min nee (O Allah, I perform Tawaf of Umrah to please You. Make it easy for me and accept it from me).Next, begin to move to the right. Draw close to the Black Stone (the Eastern cornerstone of the Kabah) and, if possible, kiss it. If cannot get close enough to kiss it, you may touch it with your hand. If you cannot get close enough to touch or kiss it, lift your hands to your ears, palms facing towards the Black Stone, and recite this short prayer: Bismillahi Allahu akbar wa lilah hil-hamd. Don not shove or fight for a chance to touch the Black Stone.Begin to circle the Kabah. Walk counter-clockwise so that the Kabah stays at your left. Circle the Kabah seven times, praying as you do so. There are no designated prayers for the Tawaf, so you may use ones from your daily life or simply pray from your heart. You may also point at the Black Stone each time you walk by it.When you have completed seven circles, you are finished. Men can now cover their right shoulder.</string>

    <string name="Perform_Saey"> Saey means "seeking" or "ritual walking". In practical terms, it means walking back and forth seven times between the hills of Safa and Marwah which are to the south and north of the Kabah, respectively. Originally, this was done outdoors, but today, the entire path is enclosed in a long gallery. When you reach the top of Safa, recite another Niyyah, saying: Allah huma inee ureeduss sa ya baynas safaa wal marwata sab ata ashwaatin lilaahi taaala fa yasir hoo lee wata qabal hu minee. (O Allah! I intend to perform seven rounds of Sa’ey between Safa and Marwah to please You. Make it easy for me and accept it from me) Then, add: Inn-as-Safa wal-Marwa-ta min Sha’aa’irillah (Indeed Safa and Marwah are among the Signs of Allah). Finally, face the Kabah and recite "Allahu Akbar" three times. Add any additional prayers you may wish, then proceed towards Marwah. As you move towards Marwah, recite: Subhan-Allah, wal-hamdu-lillah, wa la ilaha ill-Allah, wallahu Akbar, wa la haula wa la quwwata illa-billa, or, if you can\'t remember this, use the shortened form, Subhanallah, Alhamdu Lillah, Allahu Akbar. You may add any prayers you wish. At the top of Marwah, repeat the glorification of God while facing the Ka\'bah, then walk down from the hill again.When you\'ve walked back and forth seven times, you are finished.</string>

    <string name="Have_your_hair_shaved_or_clipped"> After completing the Saey, men should have their hair either completely shaved or cut short - both are permissible, though shaving is preferred. However, a man may not want to have his head shaved completely during the Umrah if he plans to complete the Hajj rites in the next few days, which also include shaving. Women should not have their heads shaved but instead may cut a lock of hair or have their hair trimmed several inches. After the ritual hair-cutting, Umrah is complete and the restrictions of Ihram are lifted. You can return to your normal activities, wear your normal clothes, etc. However, if, like many pilgrims, you will proceed to complete the Hajj in the next few days, know that you will need to re-enter Ihram to do so.</string>
    <string name="Performing_the_Rites_of_Hajj"></string>
    <string name="Reassume_Ihram_and_declare_your_intention_to_perform_Hajj">Depending upon how the trip is scheduled, most pilgrims performing the Tamattu pilgrimage have a several-day break in between their Umrah duties and their Hajj duties, so, for sake of ease, they leave the state of Ihram after their Umrah. However, as with Umrah, the Hajj requires ritual purity and meekness before God, so, at the outset of the Hajj, pilgrims re-assume the state of Ihram. As before, bathe, groom yourself, and don the proper Ihram clothes. When you are ready, say another Niyyah: Allahuma in nee u-reedul hajja fayassir hu lee wata qabal hu min nee (O Allah! I intend to perform Hajj. Please make it easy for me and accept it from me). After, say the Talbiyah three times.The rites of the Hajj last five days are that from the 8th to the 12th of Dhul-Hijjah, you must maintain in Ihram for about three days, abstaining from the activities that are forbidden to you until this period is over.</string>
    <string name="Head_to_Mina">On the first day of Hajj, pilgrims head to Mina, a town near Mecca, where they spend the rest of the day. Here, the Saudi government provides amenities - thousands upon thousands of white air-conditioned tents provide temporary housing for each years pilgrims. On the first night, no major rituals take place, so you may spend your time praying and reflecting with other pilgrims if you wish. Many pilgrims choose to say the Dhuhr, Asr, Magrib, Isha and Fajr prayers. Note that, in Mina, men and women stay in separate tents, which are located adjacent to each other. Though husbands and wives may interact, men cannot enter womens tents.</string>
    <string name="Head_to_Arafat_and_perform_Waquf">On the second day of Hajj, pilgrims travel to Arafat, a nearby mountain. Pilgrims must reach Arafat by the afternoon, because, at this time, a ritual called Waquf begins. From the time when the sun first starts to decline until the time it sets completely, pilgrims hold a vigil on a plain of Arafat during which time they pray and reflect.No specific prayers are assigned for the Waquf, so simply pray to Allah sincerely from your heart. Many pilgrims like to also spend time reflecting on the course of their life, their future, and their place in the world.</string>
    <string name="Pray_in_Muzdalifah">After sundown, pilgrims head to a place called Muzdalifah between Mina and Arafat. Here, they offer an evening prayer to God (Maghrib) and spend the night sleeping on the ground beneath the open sky.In the morning, gather pebbles, as you will use these for the Ramy "stoning" ceremony later in the day.</string>
    <string name="Perform_Ramy_in_Mina">Before the sun rises, pilgrims head back to Mina. Here, pilgrims participate in a ceremony meant to symbolize stoning the devil. Pilgrims throw seven consecutive pebbles at a special stone monument called the Jamrat al Aqabah.This ceremony can be extremely crowded, tense, and emotional. Trampling deaths, though rare, have occurred. Because of this, the elderly, sick, and injured are discouraged from participating. Instead, they may perform this later in the evening or have a friend or confidant perform the ritual in their place.</string>
    <string name="Offer_a_sacrifice"> After the Ramy ceremony, its necessary to offer an animal sacrifice (Qurbani) to God. In the past, each pilgrim did this individually; however, today, its much more common for pilgrims to simply purchase a sacrifice voucher. These vouchers signify that an animal was sacrificed in your name. After selling vouchers, qualified personnel will sacrifice a lamb for each pilgrim (or a camel for every seven pilgrims), butcher the animals, package the meat, and ship it to Muslim communities all over the world to be used to feed the poor.Animal sacrifice can be done at any point on the 10th, 11th, or 12th day of Dhul-Hijjah. If Ramy has to be postponed for any reason, wait until after Ramy to make your sacrifice.</string>
    <string name="Get_your_hair_cut_or_shaved"> As in the Umrah, pilgrims must have their hair ritually cut. Men may have their hair completely shaved or cut into a very short haircut (if a man opted for a short haircut during his Umrah, he may now want to have his hair completely shaved off, though he is not required to). Women can have a short lock of hair cut - their heads are not shaved.</string>
    <string name="Perform_the_Tawaf_and_Saey"> Just as in the Umrah, the Hajj requires pilgrims to perform the Tawaf and Saey rituals at the Kabah and the nearby hills. The rituals are performed essentially identically to how they are performed during the Umrah, but it is highly recommended that these ceremonies be done only after the stoning, sacrifice, and hair-cutting rituals.After completing the Tawaf and Saey, you are released from your state of Ihram and may resume the activities that were previously prohibited.At the end of your third day, return to Mina and spend the night there in prayer.</string>
    <string name="Repeat_Ramy_after_sundown_on_the_fourth_and_fifth_days">In Mina, you must once again participate in the stoning ritual. This time, you will not throw pebbles only at the Jamrat al Aqabah, but also at two other monuments - the Jamrat Oolah (the first jamrat) and Jamrat Wustah (middle jamrat).First, throw pebbles at the Jamrat Oolah, then praise Allah and supplicate with your hands raised (there are no assigned prayers, so you may use your own.) Repeat this for the Jamrat Wustah. Finally, throw your pebbles at the Jamrat al Aqabah, but after, you don not need to pray - you can return home.Repeat this ritual after sundown on the fifth day.</string>
    <string name="Perform_the_Farewell_Tawaf">Finally, your Hajj has come to a close. When you have finished your Hajj, complete any unfinished business you have remaining in or around Mecca first, such as shopping or meeting any friends or family. If you are planning to stay in Mecca for a few days after Hajj, then you must wait until the very end of your stay before you perform Farewell Tawaf and depart Mecca. The Farewell Tawaf is the final tawaf, walking around the Kabah seven times as before.[12] As you perform the Farewell Tawaf, reflect on the thoughts and feelings you have experienced on your Hajj and how fortunate you have been to be selected by Allah Almighty to come to His House. Offer praise and supplication to Allah. When you have finished, you should immediately proceed to gather your belongings and luggage and depart for your home. If you need to buy food for your return trip, you are allowed to do that in sha Allah, since that is not the same as shopping and is related to the return trip. After making the Hajj, many pilgrims opt to travel to Medina, the second-holiest city in Islam. Here, they can visit such holy sites as The Prophets Mosque. No Ihram is necessary to visit Medina. Note that foreign pilgrims are required to leave Saudi Arabia by the 10th of Muharram (the 1st month of the Islamic calendar).</string>

    <string name="talbiyah">لَبَّیْکَ اَللّٰھُمَّ لَبَّیْکَ لَبَّیْکَ لاَ شَرِیْکَ لَکَ لَبَّیْکَ ط اِنَّ الْحَمدَ وَالنِّعْمَۃَ لَکَ وَالْمُلْکَ لاَ شَرِیْکَ لَکَٰ.</string>

    <string name="qOne">How to change profile?</string>
    <string name="ansOne">To change/update profile open profile, then click EDIT PROFILE, make changes you want then click on UPDATE</string>
    <string name="qTwo">How to check group members?</string>
    <string name="ansTwo">Click My Group button to show your group members and there you can also see the numbers of members in your group, so that no one can enter in your group </string>
    <string name="qThree">How to read and listen pray?</string>
    <string name="ansThree">Click the Pray button to show pray, if you want to listen pray press the play icon.</string>

    <string name="no_activity">No Activity related to HAJJ Today</string>
    <string name="ninth">On the second day of Hajj, known as Yawm al-Arafat (the Day of Arafat) or Yawm al-Wuquf (the Day of Standing), pilgrims to travel to the plain of Arafat where they combine Dhuhr and Asr prayers and engage in Wuquf, the most solemn rite of the Hajj.After spending the night in Mina, you will perform the Fajr prayer in the morning. As previously mentioned, wake up at least an hour before Fajr so you can use the washing facilities and avoid the crowds.

You will now have offered five obligatory prayers at Mina before departing for Arafat.Although fasting on the Day of Arafat is very virtuous for non-pilgrims, it isn’t recommended for pilgrims. Starting immediately after Fajr Salah on the 9th of Dhul Hijjah, audibly recite Takbir al-Tashreeq at least once after every Fardh Salah, up to and including Asr Salah on the 13th of Dhul Hijjah (a total of 23 Fardh prayers).Takbir al-Tashreeq is the recitation of the following: Allahu Akbar, Allahu Akbar, La Ilaha Ilallahu Wallahu Akbar, Allahu Akbar, Wa Lillahil Hamd.It is Sunnah to perform Ghusl on the Day of Arafat. This can be done in Arafat before the Wuquf (standing) or it can be done in Mina before departing for Arafat. The camps in Arafat are more open in comparison to Mina, so it may be more comfortable for a person, particularly a woman, to perform Ghusl in Mina. The restrictions of Ihram obviously apply too, so extra care should be taken when doing Ghusl i.e. no scrubbing and ensuring shampoo / soap is unscented if used, etc.Depart from Mina after sunrise, as this was the practice of the Prophet ﷺ. The distance from Mina to Arafat is about 13 kilometres (8 miles).

Most pilgrims tend to reach Arafat before or after Dhuhr, although delays may occur due to traffic congestion. Don’t panic if you’re still in Mina at this time and you feel you are late; your tour operator will ensure you reach your destination. Use this time wisely; you may engage in Dhikr, make Dua, take a shower or have breakfast.

As you leave, traffic may flow very slowly and you may find that it gets quite hot on the bus. Ensure you take cold drinking water and some snacks for your journey.

If you’re a woman and get separated from your husband / Mahram, you must ensure you reach Arafat, even if you have to travel alone. Look for a group of women to travel with if you get separated.If you elect to travel to Arafat by foot, keep in mind that it will probably be the most challenging walk you will encounter during the course of your Hajj. The walk is quite lengthy, particularly if you’re from Europe, as the Europa camps are situated on the other side of Arafat, meaning the distance of the journey will exceed 8 miles. Finding your camp upon arrival in Arafat may also prove fairly challenging. It is also worth noting that the Prophet ﷺ rode from Mina to Arafat on a conveyance, so travelling from Mina to Arafat by foot is not a Sunnah practice.

If you decide to walk, there will be water taps, washing facilities, benches to rest on, people selling refreshments and medical facilities at regular intervals.For your Hajj to be deemed valid, you must perform Wuquf al-Arafat i.e. you must spend a portion of time in Arafat between midday and the beginning of Fajr on the following day. If you don’t reach Arafat during this period, your Hajj will be regarded as incomplete.

If you arrive early, take some time to rest and get some sleep, as the time of Arafat doesn’t begin until after midday. Some people erroneously start their Dua for Arafat before midday and rest in the evening; this is an incorrect practice and should be avoided.

During the course of the day, you should spend as much time in Dhikr and Ibadah as possible. It is perhaps a day that you will never experience again, so make the most of it.</string>
    <string name="tenth">After dawn, </string>
    <string name="rest">Do these</string>







    <!--AIzaSyBJzYXIrO28n6UzW70H88-uxPcEissfAwA-->

    <!--AIzaSyAqXlBp6zYMOumUffHhoPby5HvF0nKckSE-->


    <string name="google_maps_api_key">AIzaSyAqXlBp6zYMOumUffHhoPby5HvF0nKckSE</string>
    <!-- Strings related to login -->
    <string name="prompt_email">Email</string>
    <string name="prompt_password">Password (optional)</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in">Sign in or register</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in_short">Sign in</string>
    <string name="action_sign_out">Sign out</string>
    <string name="error_invalid_email">This email address is invalid</string>
    <string name="error_invalid_password">This password is too short</string>
    <string name="error_incorrect_password">This password is incorrect</string>
    <string name="error_field_required">This field is required</string>
    <string name="resend_verification_email">Resend Verification Email</string>
    <string name="forgot_password">Forgot Password</string>
    <string name="register">Register</string>
    <string name="sign_in">Sign In</string>
    <string name="password">Password</string>
    <string name="tabian_consulting_logo">Ahmed Consulting Logo</string>
    <string name="email_registration">Email Registration</string>
    <string name="email">Email</string>
    <string name="confirm_password">Confirm Password</string>

    <!-- Firestore Strings -->
    <string name="collection_users">Users</string>
    <string name="collection_chatrooms">Chatrooms</string>
    <string name="collection_chat_messages">Chat Messages</string>
    <string name="collection_chatroom_user_list">User List</string>
    <string name="collection_user_locations">User Locations</string>

    <!-- Intent extras -->
    <string name="intent_chatroom">intent_chatroom</string>
    <string name="intent_user_list">intent_user_list</string>
    <string name="intent_user_locations">intent_user_locations</string>
    <string name="intent_location">intent_location</string>

    <!-- Service and Broadcasts -->
    <string name="gps_location">gps_location</string>


    <!-- Fragments Names -->
    <string name="fragment_user_list">User List</string>
    <string name="fragment_image_list">Image List</string>

    <!-- Other Strings -->
    <string name="action_create_chatroom">Create Chatroom</string>
    <string name="action_leave_chatroom">Leave chatroom</string>
    <string name="action_chatroom_user_list">User list</string>
    <string name="action_profile">Profile</string>
</resources>
